Guide to the Everett Cherrington Hughes Papers 1922-1982
University of Chicago Library
- Series III: Course Material
  - Subseries 2: University of Chicago, 1938-1961
    - Sociology 210, lecture notes, exams, handouts, class notes, 1958 (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Sociology 210, syllabus, lecture notes, exams, notes, handouts, 1960 (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Sociology-Anthropology 240, Life Cycle of Institutions, outline, lectures, 1947, 1949 (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Sociology-Anthropology 240, lecture, lecture notes, 1950 (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Sociology 315A, Collective Behavior, class schedule, reading list, bibliography, papers, student work, notes, reprints, 1959 (Box 76, Folder 1-2)
    - Sociology 315A/339, Collective Behavior, reading lists, bibliographies, papers, reprints, notes, 1960 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Sociology 325, Race and Culture Contacts, student assignments, 1943 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Sociology 325, bibliographies, course outlines, notes assignments, reprints, 1949 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Sociology 325, lectures, 1950, notes, assignments, 1947-1959 (Box 76, Folder 6-8)
    - Sociology 325, papers, bibliographies, 1948-1959 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Sociology 325, papers, bibliographies, lectures, notes, "Ethnic Relations in Guatemala" by Sol Tax, 1948, reprints, 1948-1951 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Sociology 325, "What's in a Name?" lecture, notes, correspondence, 1950 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Sociology 325, lectures, notes, assignments, handouts, papers, reprints, 1952 (Box 77, Folder 2-4)
    - Sociology 325, student bibliographies, notes, papers, 1953 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Sociology 325, syllabus, reading list, exams, notes, 1957 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 325, handouts, notes, reprints, n.d. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 330, Contemporary Communities, handouts, course description and outline, reading lists, papers, exams, reprints, 1960-1961 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Sociology 332, Industry and the Community, lecture notes, class diary, notes, 1946-1951 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Sociology 332, lecture notes, 1947 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Sociology 332, lectures, lecture transcriptions, handouts, 1951 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Sociology 348, Sociology of Occupations and Professions, lecture notes, memorandum, handouts, assignments, exams, 1942-1959 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Sociology 348, lectures, 1949-1950 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Sociology 348, lectures, 1948-1952 (Box 78, Folder 3-4)
    - Sociology 348, lectures, 1952 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Sociology 350, Social Institutions, exams, notes, McGill notes, 1936-1940 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 350, notes, exams, correspondence, 1941-1956 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 350, memorandum, assignments, exams, reading lists, notes, 1945-1957 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Sociology 350, "Of Time and Religion," bibliographies, notes, 1944-1947 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Sociology 350, lectures, 1950 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Sociology 350, "Bastard Institutions," lecture, 1951 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Sociology 350, "Going Concerns," lectures, notes, student work, 1951-1957 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Sociology 350, assignments, exams, reading lists, 1956-1957 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Sociology 395, Comparative Law and the Sociology of Law, bibliography, 1945 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Sociology 407, Seminar on Methods and Training in Field Observation, abstracts of meetings, handouts, 1952 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Sociology 426, Economic and Cultural Growth in West European Urban Society, with Sylvia Thrupp and Gustav B. Grunebaum, lectures, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 436, Reading of Simmel's Sociologie, bibliographies, handouts, reprints, 1954 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 448, Occupations and Professions, handouts, correspondence, 1960 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Social Science 431, Personality Correlates of Different Patterns of Response to Cultural Marginality, abstracts, lectures, bibliographies, 1952 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Social Science 431, Seminar in Race and Culture, Culture Contact in Israel, Sol Tax, notes, correspondence, 1955 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Frontiers of Contact, Seminar on Racial and Cultural Contacts, summary of meetings by Albert Parry, notes, 1939-1945 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Race Relations Seminar, student thesis abstract, historical statement of course, research project outlines, notes, 1939-1949 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Seminar on the Comparative Study of Cities, papers, 1955-1956 (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 3: Brandeis University, 1961-1968
    - Sociology 116b, Multi-Ethnic Societies, exams, assignments, reading lists, bibliographies, 1961-1967 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Sociology 116b, lecture notes, reading list, 1964 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Sociology 116b, memorandum, lecture notes, exams, 1966-1967 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Sociology 116b, assignments, memorandum, handouts, class diary, calendar, notes, 1966-1968 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Sociology 116b, lecture notes, handouts, exams, 1968 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Sociology 116b, language of race relations, manuscript, notes, handouts, memorandum, 1967 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 116b, course evaluation, correspondence, 1969 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 117a/203, Sociology of Work and Occupations, field studies, memorandum, assignments, handouts, notes, 1961-1962 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Sociology 117a/203, syllabus, exam, lecture notes, class diaries, bibliography, handouts, 1962-1966 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Sociology 117a/203, reading lists, assignment, class diary, calendar, notes, 1967 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Sociology 117a/203, Boston College Sociology 260, 760, memoranda, handouts, 1971-1972 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - Sociology 118a, Social Institutions, exams, lecture notes, memoranda, correspondence, reading lists, student papers, 1961-1966 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - Sociology 120a, Fiction about Africa, bibliographies, handouts, correspondence, memorandum, notes, daily calendar for Spring 1961 at University of Kansas, 1960-1961 (Box 80, Folder 13-15)
    - Sociology 120a, bibliographies, notes, correspondence, 1961-1969 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Sociology 120a, reading list, documents, 1961 (Box 81, Folder 2-3)
    - Sociology 190b, Social Organization of Medical Settings, Everett C. Hughes and Irving K. Zola, reading lists, notes, memoranda from Irving K. Zola, 1967-1968 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Sociology 200, exams, 1962 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Sociology 203, Introduction to Field Studies, assignments, handouts, 1963 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 203, Field Methods in Sociological Research, handouts, memorandum from colleague, notes, 1963-1964 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 203, course outline, assignments, Sociology 207, Natural History of Educational Enterprise, handouts, notes, student work, 1963-1964 (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Sociology 203, memoranda from colleagues, bibliography, 1965-1966 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Sociology 227a, Seminar on Occupations, class notes, minutes, 1964 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Sociology 301, Advanced Field Training Seminar, syllabus, notes, student work, 1967 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Sociology 330, Contemporary Communities, course outline, reading list, ca. 1959 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Informal Seminar on the Student, handouts, papers, notes, memoranda, 1962 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - Adult Education Program, brochures, correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 81, Folder 14)
  - Subseries 4: Boston College, 1968-1977
    - Sociology 120, Social Institutions, class diary, assignments, reading lists, notes, handouts, 1968 (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - Sociology 120, class diary, exams, assignments, reading lists, notes, 1969-1971 (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - Sociology 146, Multi-Racial and Multi-Ethnic Societies, memoranda, reading list, assignments, bibliographical notes, notes, 1970-1971 (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - Sociology 146, handouts, class diary, notes, "Social Integration and Police Authority" by Michael Banton, conference paper, 1970 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Sociology 146, reading lists, bibliography, 1971 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Sociology 146, exams, reading list, assignments, memoranda, notes, class diary, calendar, 1972 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Sociology 146, reading lists, assignments, handouts, exam, class diary, calendar, memoranda, 1973 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Sociology 146, course description, assignments, memoranda, class diary, notes, 1974-1975 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Sociology 146, exams, assignments, handouts, course description, reading lists, memoranda, notes, 1975-1977 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 146, race and minorities, class notes, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 146, American negro, general, memoranda, notes, bibliography, 1969-1976 (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Sociology 160, bibliography, assignments, notes, 1969 (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Sociology 184, Evolution of Interaction, Mammals, Primates, Humans, with Jeanne Guillemin handouts, memoranda, notes, 1973-1976 (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Sociology 184, handouts, reading lists, assignments, syllabus, memoranda to Guillemin, notes, 1975 (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Sociology 184, feeling, sex, ecology, memoranda, notes, 1975 (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - Sociology 184, costume, odor, the body, handouts, memoranda, notes, 1975 (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Sociology 184, assignments, handouts, reading lists, syllabus, course diary, memoranda to Guillemin, notes, 1976 (Box 82, Folder 14)
    - Sociology 260, Work and Occupations, reading list, notes, 1969 (Box 82, Folder 15)
    - Sociology 260, handouts, memoranda, notes, 1970-1971 (Box 82, Folder 16)
    - Sociology 260, careers, handouts, n.d. (Box 82, Folder 17)
    - Sociology 262, American Corporation, with Severyn T. Bruyn, handouts, notes, memorandum, "The Contradictions of Modern Business" by Severyn T. Bruyn, n.d. (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Sociology 320, Sociologists at Work, assignments, handouts, notes, class diary, 1975 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Sociology 346, Multi-Ethnic and Multi-Racial Societies, reading list, memorandum, notes, class diary, correspondence, handouts, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Sociology 565, Work and Occupations, notes, 1946-1967 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Sociology 565, assignments, bibliography, exams, notes, course outline, class diary, 1972-1976 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Sociology 569, Ecology of Higher Education, course diary, memoranda, notes, 1972-1973 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Sociology 570, Social Institutions, reading lists, handouts, 1974-1975 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Sociology 714, Sociological Study of Contemporary Institutions, handout, 1973 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Sociology 760, Social Movements, Work and Careers, memoranda, assignments, handouts, 1972-1973 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Sociology 799, Reading and Research, correspondence, 1977 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Social behavior, baboons and early man, notes, ca. 1975 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Race and ethnic relations, correspondence, course outlines, 1969-1970 (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Teaching evaluations by students, 1976 (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 5: Visiting Seminars and Lectures
    - UniversitÈ Laval, Cultural Contacts, lectures, 1942 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - UniversitÈ Laval, Centennial Seminar, "Regionalism in French Canada," lecture, correspondence, August 20-23, 1967 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - McGill University, Post War Housing and Community Planning Lecture Series, lecture, March 14, 1944 (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - McGill University, seminar schedule, outline, class diary, 1965 (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - UniversitÈ de MontrÈal, lecture, February 1962 (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - UniversitÈ de MontrÈal, seminar notes, Winter 1965 (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - UniversitÈ de MontrÈal, student field work, 1965 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - UniversitÈ de MontrÈal, seminars, lectures, memoranda, notes, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Carleton University, notes, correspondence, February 1962 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Stanford University, Educational Institutions, class diary, notes, handouts, Summer 1963 (Box 84, Folder 4-6)
    - Vienna seminar, lectures, outlines, notes, Summer 1964 (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Harvard University, Changing Roles and Functions in Mental Health, course description, course calendar, reading list, 1973 (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - University of Toronto, Seminar on Canadian Society, notes, 1977 (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 6: Miscellaneous Lectures
    - Social institutions, frontier technology, lecture, notes, ca. 1929 (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Social institutions, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 84, Folder 11-13)
    - Social institutions, documents, memoranda, notes, 1961 (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - Social institutions, institutional office and personal role, n.d. (Box 84, Folder 15)
    - Social institutions, role of Chicago Real Estate Board, the family, role of professional institutions, the guild and the family, selection of persons, occupations, notes, n.d. (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Max Weber, William B. Hocking, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Social control, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - The Racket, notes, ca. 1930 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Methods of social research, lectures, assignments, notes, Laval University, ca. 1930s (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Voluntary associations, lectures, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Institutions, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 85, Folder 7-9)
    - Institutions, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 86, Folder 1-2)
    - Institutions, control and the code, notes, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Institutions, role and office, lectures, notes, correspondence, ca 1930s (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Institutions, role and office, notes, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Institutions, institutions in process, notes, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Institutions, classification and methods of study, lectures, notes, ca. 1939 (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Institutions, "Introduction," lecture, notes, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Institutions, Park and Burgess revision, outline, notes, correspondence with Lewis C. Copeland, 1940 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Elementary institutions, manuscript, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 86, Folder 10-11)
    - Institutions and war, notes, n.d. (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Institutions and persons, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Chicago Park District Convention, notes, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Sect and social change, bibliographies, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Ecology of institutions, notes, correspondence, R. D. McKenzie, 1935-1936 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Ecology, notes, student work, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Human ecology, notes, ca. 1930s (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Race relations, bibliographies, 1937-1967 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Race mixture, notes, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Multi-ethnic societies, geographic list, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Negroes in industry, research interviews, charts, Chicago, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - War propaganda, publications, 1940-1941 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Systems of institutions, notes, 1942-1945, 1963, 1968-1970 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Careers, lectures, 1949, 1952, 1955 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Careers, proposed chart for collecting personal data on careers, notes, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Careers, notes, n.d. (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - Seminar on Professions, Frankfurt, correspondence, notes, papers, 1957-1958 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Work, bibliography, lectures, n.d. (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Work and occupations, bibliographies, 1946-1969 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Study of institutions, notes, ca. 1926 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Study of institutions, notes, memoranda, 1955, 1961 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Study of institutions, lectures, correspondence, reprint, 1963-1968 (Box 88, Folder 6-7)
    - Schools, notes, reading lists, exam, 1966 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Problems in Comparative Sociological Research, bibliography, 1967 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Colonialism, notes, memoranda, 1972 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Changing roles and functions in mental health, course outline, notes, 1973 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Nomenclature, notes, 1973 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Occupations, economic relationships, papers, notes, ca. 1973 (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Occupations, notes, bibliography, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Misc. notes (from file boxes) ca. 1930's-1940's (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 7: Student Work
    - Ahmann, Mathew, Sociology 325, term paper, 1957 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Allon, Natalie, field notes, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 4-5)
    - Anderson, Douglas, Sociology 325, "Racial Contact in Jackson Park," n.d. (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Argyrakis, Harriett, class work, interviews, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Aronoff, Marilyn, "Northeastern: The College of Liberal Arts and the `Uses' of the University," "University College: A Perspective on Education in a Marginal Institution," 1965 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Bagdones, Joseph, Sociology 350, "Brighton Park," 1939 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Beaulieu, Maurice, Sociology 650, "Relations Ethniques et Carriere," 1965 (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Behrens, Judy, Sociology 117a, progress report, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Berlew, David, "Psychology as a Profession," 1958 (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - Binstock, Jeanne, "Purposes and Goals of American Colleges," outline, notes, n.d. (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Bourgeois, Charles, "Situational Perspectives of Premedical Students and Their Effect on Academic and Career Goals," dissertation proposal, field notes, correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Brooks, David, Sociology 260, "The Detailer and the Industrial Salesman," 1972 (Box 89, Folder 15)
    - Caron, Monique, "Analyse descriptive d'une compagnie d'assurance," 1965 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Carter, Barbara, "Social Life in a Training School for Delinquent Girls," thesis proposal, field notes, progress report, 1964-1968 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Cassidy and Verdet, "Report on a Sect," ca. 1960s (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Cless, D., "The Forum, An Exercise in Observation with a Few Comments," 1966 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Cohen, Anne, "Autobiographical Sketch," 1964 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Cornehl, Gisela, Gerd Gruda and Werner Thoennessen, "Sozialwissenschaft als Beruf: Projekt Zur Soziologischen Studie eines Berufes," 1963 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Cox, Oliver, "The Negroes' Use of Their Buying Power in Chicago as a Means of Securing Employment, A New Application of an Old Method," ca. 1930s (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Davis, Alexander, Sociology 201, "Change of Village Life under the Hitler Government," 1938 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Desardins, Lucylle, Sociology 302, "Education and Ethnic Attitude Changes," 1965 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - DÈsy, Jacques, "Carrieres et mariages inter ethniques," 1965 (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - Edwards, Janet, "The 24th Hour: Problems and Promise of a Therapeutic Community in Action," field notes, 1967 (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - Emerson, Robert, "Some Aspects of Labeling in the Juvenile Court," seminar paper, thesis proposal, 1966 (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - Feldman, Harvey, "A Proposal to Study the Career of the Lower Socio-Economic Drug User in His Local Neighborhood," 1967 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Frenette, Jean-Guy, "Relations ethniques chez les mineurs," 1965 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Gandreau, ...mile, autobiographical sketch, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Gertner, Rosalind, "An Introduction to Chiropractic: Practitioners and Practice," 1968 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Godin, AndrÈ, "Profil d'un enseignant," 1965 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Halsey, A. H., "The Changing Functions of Universities," 1959 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Hare, Nathaniel, untitled paper for Race and Culture Contact class, 1957 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Hill, Robert, "When the Playing Stops," 1972 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Holstrom, Lynda, field notes, 1966 (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Houtart, Francois, "The Church and City Life," lectures, 1953 (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Jamieson, Stuart, thesis corrections, correspondence, 1938 (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Joffee, Carole, Sociology 99, papers on protest marches, 1966-1967, "Coping with `Dirty Work': The Case of Abortion," 1979 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Judge, Stephen, "Transitional Zone Neighborhoods and Their Effects upon Professional Businesses," 1971 (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - Keyfitz, Nathan, "Can People of Different Speech Work Together?" 1963 (Box 91, Folder 14)
    - Keyserling, Sigrid von, Sociology 210, "Mister H.: A Management Consultant," 1963 (Box 91, Folder 15)
    - Kraft, Philip, Sociology 99, "The Lady and/or the Tiger: Chelsea and the War on Poverty," 1966 (Box 91, Folder 16)
    - Krupnick, Susan and Susan Shapiro, "Nazareth," 1967 (Box 91, Folder 17)
    - Lamarche, Claire, "Sociologie de l'education," 1965 (Box 91, Folder 18)
    - Laufer, Robert, "The Experimental College and its Social Origins: Historical Limitations on Experimental Programs," "An Introduction to the General Division of Kent University," bibliography, 1966 (Box 91, Folder 19)
    - Laurin, Nicole, "Problemes liÈs ‡ l'origine ethnique et au sexe dans la carriËre des petits bureaucrates," correspondence, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 20)
    - Lavery, Robert, "A Sociological Autobiography," 1965 (Box 91, Folder 21)
    - Lazarus, "Sex," n.d. (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Lee, Moon-hwi, Sociology 203, genealogy, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Lehr, Eugene, "Careers: A Case Study," 1963 (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - LÈveillÈ, Yves, "...volution dans la conception professionnelle de l'Ètudiante infirmiËre? Image de soi et rÈalitÈ," n.d. (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Liazos, A., Sociology 301, "The Self in an Institutional Setting," 1967 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Lieberson, Stanley, "The Post Office," memorandum, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Marceau, Claude, "L'Homme d'affaires canadien-franÁais," memorandum, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 7)
    - Mayer, Robert, "Profil d'une carriËre," 1965 (Box 92, Folder 8)
    - McDowell, Harold, "Choice and Retension in an Osteopathic Clinic," 1947 (Box 92, Folder 9)
    - McDowell, Harold, "The Principal's Role in a Metropolitan School System, Its Functions and Variations," ca. 1952 (Box 92, Folder 10)
    - McNatt, Glenn, "Identity and Consciousness in the Literature of the Black American of the Twentieth Century," correspondence, 1974 (Box 92, Folder 11)
    - Meymand, N. L., "Festivals and Holidays," 1970 (Box 92, Folder 12)
    - Moussea, Monique, "Orientation about the French Canadian Minority Problem," n.d. (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - Naga, field notes, n.d. (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - Nagarajan, J., night club field notes, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 15)
    - Nakagawa, G. F., hospital field notes, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Needelman, Jean, Sociology 276, "Tentative Research Project," 1950 (Box 92, Folder 17)
    - Nicolaus, Martin, Sunday Mass field notes, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 18)
    - Novogradsky, Charles, Sociology 116B, "Professional Sport and the Negro Athlete: Notes on Identity and Institution," memorandum, 1967 (Box 92, Folder 19)
    - Offenbach, Lilly, "A Genealogy," "Analysis of an Institution," 1963, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 20)
    - Ostow, Robin, "A Description of the Career and Some of the Career Problems of Optometrists," 1971, "Sicilians in a Sardic Community," 1972, "Coping With Failure in Psychotherapy," 1975 (Box 92, Folder 21)
    - Ostow, Robin, "Social Stratification and Optometry Students," 1971 (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Ostow, Robin, "Telemula: From a Self-Sufficient Herding Community to a Labour-Exporting Hinterland," n.d. (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Ostow, Robin, "Demography of Labour Migration in Central Sardinia," n.d. (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Papanek, Hanna, "In Loco Parentis," correspondence, reprints, 1962-1963 (Box 93, Folder 4)
    - Papanek, Hanna, "Men, Women and Work: A Comparison of Separate Worlds in Muslim South Asia and Two-Person Single Careers in America," 1972 (Box 93, Folder 5)